- 준비됐어?
- 이것만 끝내고 가자
- You ready to go?
- Let me just finish this.
야, 로스? 이것 봐라
Hey, Ross. Check this out.
그래, 난 공 못돌려
Yeah, I can't do that.
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 이거 봤어?
- What are you doing?
- Have you seen this?
대학 동창회 사이트가 새로 생겼어
It's our new alumni website
for college.
자신의 요즘 근황을
올리면 다들 볼수가 있어
You can post messages for people,
let everyone know what you're up to.
잘됐네, 내가 실업자에 애도
없다는걸 더 빨리 소문낼수 있겠어
Oh, great. A faster way to tell people
that I'm unemployed and childless.
그보다 다른 동창들의 근황을
알수 있다는게 더 재미있어
It's actually interesting to find
out what people are doing.
안드레아 리치 기억나?
Remember Andrea Rich?
너한테 딱지 놨던 키큰 여자애?
That tall girl that wouldn't sleep
with you?
그래, 걔가 하던 인터넷 회사는
망했고 보트사고로 한쪽 귀를 잃었대
Well, her Internet company went under,
and she lost an ear in a boating accident.
그럼 이젠 너 딱지 안놓겠구나
Bet she'd sleep with you now.
아냐, 벌써 이메일 보내봤어
No, I already e-mailed her.
네 근황은 뭐라고 썼는데?
Let me see what you wrote
about yourself.
"고생물학 박사
아이는 둘.."
"Doctor of paleontology, two kids."
캐롤과는 관심분야가
달라서 헤어졌다고?
Wait a second. You split with Carol
because you had different interests?
캐롤의 관심분야도
"여자"라서 헤어진게 아니구?
I think you split with Carol because
you had one very similar interest.
이건 나중에 끝내야겠다
코트 가져올게
I'm gonna finish this later, okay?
Let me just grab my coat.
그래!
Okay!
2분사이에 공 돌리는 법을
익혔을 거라고 생각했니?!
What, did you think you learned how
to do it in the last two minutes?
나머지는 우리가 대신 써주자
Maybe we finish this for him.
'난 실험실에서 공룡을 복제했어'
Also, I cloned a dinosaur in my lab.
'그 공룡은 지금 내 애인이야'
She is now my girlfriend.
'사람들이 뭐라고 해도 그녀와
나눈 사랑은 생애 최고였어!'
I don't care what society says,
it's the best sex I've ever had.
- 전송!
- 안돼! 너무 심하잖아!
- And send.
- No, no.. You can't do that to him.
- 가자
- 공 던져!
- All right, let's go.
- Dude!
넌 실내에서 공 가지고 놀
자격이 없다는거 몰라?
I think you made it clear you can't be
trusted with the ball inside the house.
전송!
And send.
프렌즈 시즌 9
'로스를 추모하며..?'
어서와
농구 어땠어?
Hey. How was basketball?
재미있었는데 챈들러가
손가락에 눈이 찔렸어
It was fun. Right up until Chandler
got a finger in the eye.
어머, 누가 그랬어?
Oh, no! Who did that?
챈들러가
Chandler. Yeah.
안녕, 엠마?
Hey!
- 레이첼?
- 응?
- Rach?
- Yeah?
헉시가 엠마 요람 안에서
뭘하는 거지?
What's Huggsy doing
in the crib with Emma?
엠마가 기어다니다가 헉시를
보고는 잘 놀길래 같이 재웠어
She was just crawling around and found
him, so I just let her sleep with him.
- 괜찮지?
- 그럼! 물론이지!
- That's all right, isn't it?
- Of course. Yeah.
그냥 동물인형인걸
애들 장난감이잖아, 어른은 필요없어
It's a stuffed animal, you know?
It's for kids. Not for adults.
그건 나도 안다구!
I know that.
정말이야?
너 헉시 사랑하잖아
Joey, you're sure? I mean,
I know how much you love him.
레이첼, 확실히 알아둬
난 헉시를 사랑하는게 아냐
Rachel, let's be clear on this, okay?
I do not love Huggsy.
적당히 좋아하는 것뿐이지
I like him a normal amount.
엠마는 헉시를 너무 사랑해!
All right. Well, Emma loves him.
왜 아니겠어?
헉시가 얼마나 멋진 녀석인데!
Yeah. Well, why wouldn't she?
He's a wonderful person!
- 안녕
- 피비, 어때?
- Hi.
- Hey, Phoebe. How you doing?
- 기분좀 나아졌니?
- 이별은 정말 싫어!
- You feeling better?
- Breaking up sucks.
- 마이크가 너무 보고싶어
- 그래, 힘들거야
- Oh, I really miss Mike.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
기분전환 하려고 별짓 다했어!
작곡도 해보려고 했지만..
I've tried everything to feel better.
I even tried writing a song about it..
"으아아아!"라는 가사는
운율 맞추기가 너무 어렵더라구!
but I can't think of anything
that rhymes with:
네가 어떤지 알아
Oh, I so know how you feel.
리처드랑 헤어지는건
내 인생에서 가장 힘들었던 일이야
Breaking up with Richard was
the hardest thing I've ever done in my life.
알았어, 또 리처드
얘기했으니깐 벌받을게
All right, fine, I'll put another dollar
in the Richard jar.
모니카, 네가 나좀 도와줘
Hey, Monica, I'm gonna need
your help getting through this.
내 도움은 필요없어?
You're saying you're
not gonna need my help?
됐어, 때가 되면
너한테 도와달라고 할게
No. When I get to the point
where I'm ready..
마이크 흉내를 내며 놀려도
내가 잘 받아들일수 있을때
to hear cruel, mocking jokes
about Mike, I'm gonna come to you.
좋아! 생각해둔게 세가지 있어
아! 방금 네번째 것이 생각났어!
Oh, good, because I've already thought
of three. Four! I just thought of a fourth!
난 옳은 선택을 한거야
Okay. I mean, I know
I did the right thing.
마이크는 결혼을 원치 않았고
Mike never wants to get married..
난 미래가 없는 관계는
원치 않으니까
and I shouldn't be in a relationship
that has no future.
하지만 마이크가 그리울 거야
But pretty soon,
I'm gonna miss him so much..
그러면 네가 날 말려줘야해
I'm gonna want to see him again,
and you have to stop me.
알았어, 걱정마
Okay, you got it.
내가 너무 심한걸까?
Unless..
Am I being too crazy about this?
미래가 없는 관계라고 해서
사랑도 없어지는건 아니잖아?
All right, so there's no future. But that
doesn't mean we still can't have fun.
- 나 도와달라고 한거 취소할게
- 정말?
- You know what? Forget what I said.
- Really?
- 좋아, 네가 원한다면
- 너 시험해 본건데 불합격이야
- All right, if that's what you want.
- That was a test, and you just failed.
이런!
그런 뻔한 실수를 하다니!
Damn it! Rookie mistake!
내가 공룡이랑 사랑을 나눠?!
I have sex with dinosaurs?
어디선가 그런걸 읽은것 같다
I believe I read that somewhere.
웃기지도 않을 뿐더러
물리적으로 불가능한 일이야!
Not only is it not funny,
it's physically impossible! Okay?
공룡의 종류에 따라선 내가 무려
1.8m나 되는.. 아무튼 안웃겨!
Depending on the species, I'd have
to have a 6-foot-long.. It's not funny!
제 생각은 다른데요?
I respectfully disagree.
그런걸 우리 동창 사이트에
올리면 어떡해?!
I can't believe you put that
on my alumni page.
- 뭐어때? 아무도 그런거 안봐
- 오늘 거기 올린 네소식은
- Who cares? Nobody reads those.
- You better hope not..
정말 아무도 안봐야겠더라
because I just read what
you put on your page.
- 난 아무것도 안썼는데?
- 아뇨! 제 생각은 다른데요!
- I don't have a page.
- Oh, I respectfully disagree!
헉시?
Huggsy?
헉시
Huggsy.
내 펭귄 내놔!
I want my penguin.
귀여운것! 순진한 얼굴로
천사같이 자는구나!
Look at you. All sweet and innocent,
sleeping like an angel.
엠마의 작고 통통한 손에
안겨서 말야!
With Emma's chubby little hands
wrapped around you.
괜찮아, 엠마
계속자
It's okay, Emma. You stay asleep.
침대에서 떨어져!
난 무기를 갖고 있다!
Step away from the crib!
I have a weapon!
괜찮아! 나야, 레이첼!
머리 끈 내려놔!
It's okay! It's okay, Rach!
It's me! Put down the scrunchie.
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 엠마가 뒤적이는 소리가 나서..
- What are you doing?
- Well, I heard Emma stirring..
헉시를 가까이 놔주려고
들어온 거야
so I came in to make sure
she could reach Huggsy.
고마워, 일어난 김에
화장실에나 가야겠다
Oh, thanks. All right, well, now that
I'm up, I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
여기있다, 엠마
Okay, there you go, sweetie.
아직 끝나지 않았어!
This isn't over!
잠깐만
오빠가 왜 동창들에게
Wait a second. Why would
Ross tell everyone in your class..
자기가 게이라고 말했지?
that you are "as gay
as the day is long"?
난 로스가 공룡과
사랑을 나눴다고 썼거든
Because I told everyone
he slept with dinosaurs.
그건 누가 봐도 농담이지!
하지만 이건 진짜 같잖아!
Well, that's clearly a joke.
This could easily be true.
자기가 받아!
하루종일 축하인사 전화야!
Would you get that, please? People have
been calling to congratulate me all day.
여보세요?
Hello?
지금 없는데요
전 집 사람이에요
No, he's not here.
Yeah, this is his wife.
네, 저도 충격이었어요
Yeah. Well, it came
as quite a shock to me too!
자꾸만 영화 물랑루즈를
보자고 할때 눈치챘어야 했어요!
Well, I guess I should've known. He just
kept making me watch Moulin Rouge.
빨리 끊어!
Hang up! Hang up!
그리고 그 영화는 명작이야!
And that was a great movie.
로스한테 복수할거야!
I'm so gonna get back at Ross.
좋아! 맛좀 봐라!
Oh, yeah, this'll show him.
Here we go.
- 어떻게 할건데?
- 두고 봐!
- What are you doing?
- Oh, you'll see, my friend!
내가 죽었어?
I'm dead?
젊은 나이에 안됐다
And so young.
내가 죽었다고 올려?
이건 절대 웃을 일이 아냐!
Posting that I died?
That really isn't funny.
어떻게 죽었는지 알면 우스울걸?
Well, how you died was funny.
'비행선에 치어' 죽은게 우습냐?
Oh, please. Hit by a blimp?
미국에서 1년에 한명 이상이
그렇게 죽는대
It kills over one Americans every year.
말도 안돼! 동창들이 모두
내가 죽은줄 알거 아냐!
Unbelievable. My classmates
are gonna think I'm dead.
교수님, 부모님도 전화 받으실 테고!
My professors. My parents
are gonna get phone calls!
다른 사람들 감정은 생각 안해?
You're messing with
people's feelings here.
그러는 넌? 어제 스턴 교수님이 같이
플로리다에 가자고 전화하셨더라!
You wanna talk about people's feelings?
You should have heard how hurt..
내가 안된다고 했더니
얼마나 상심하셨는줄 알아?!
Professor Stern was when I told him
I wouldn't be able to go to Key West!
너 도가 지나쳤어!
좋아!
You've really crossed a line here.
But that's okay.
나 지금 포토샵이랑
게이 포르노 사러
Because I'm on my way
to buy some Photoshop software..
가는 길이거든!
and a stack of gay porn.
두고봐! 네 '게이선언'을 아주 생생한
그래픽으로 선전해 줄테니까!
That's right. Your coming-out
is about to get real graphic!
마이크 보고싶어!
God, I wish Mike were here.
지금 마이크랑 같이 있으면
둘이 뭐하려구?
Okay, if Mike were here, what
would the two of you be doing?
짐승이니?!
이제 4시밖에 안됐어!
What are you, animals?
It's 4:00 in the afternoon.
전화할래! 그냥 얘기만 할거야
그건 괜찮잖아
I gotta call him. Just to talk to him.
There's no harm in that.
피비, 그렇게 시작하는 거야
That's how it starts. "I don't need
to eat the cake, I'll just smell the icing.
"케이크는 안먹을 거야
크림냄새만 맡아야지"
"한번 찍어먹는건 괜찮겠지
한 두 조각은 괜찮을 거야"
Why not just a little sliver?"
Or, "Okay, just a slice or two."
그러면 금방 100kg 넘고
The next thing you know,
you're 210 pounds..
터널 미끄럼틀에 꽉끼게 된다고!
and you get wedged in going
down the tunnel slide!
- 정말 그랬어?
- 전기톱을 써서
- That's not true, is it?
- They had to cut me out..
날 빼내야 했어!
with the Jaws of Life.
힘든건 알지만
Phoebe, honey, I know this is hard.
얘기 나누면 보고싶어질 거야
But look, if you talk to him,
then you're gonna want to see him.
보고나면 다시 함께
지내고 싶어질 거고
And if you see him, you're gonna
wanna get back together.
너도 그걸 바라진 않지?
And I know that's not what you want.
전화 이리내
All right, so give me your phone.
자
Here.
- 핸드폰도
- 알았어
- And now your cell.
- Okay.
자
There you go.
- 이게 네 핸드폰이야?
- 그래
- This is your cell phone?
- Yes.
이게 네가 '요즘'
쓰는 핸드폰이냐구!
This is your current cell phone?
그래, 난 복고풍이 좋거든
Yes. It reminds me of a simpler time.
피비, 핸드백 어디 있니?
Phoebe? Where's your purse?
- 안돼!
- 싫어!
- Hey! No!
- No!
- 이리줘
- 안돼! 못줘!
- Give it to me!
- You can't have it!
- 이리내!
- 싫어!
- Give it to me!
- No!
- 그러면 못뺏을줄 알구?
- 해봐!
- I'll go in there!
- Oh, yeah.
- 이리 내놔!
- 싫어!
- Phoebe, come here!
- No!
- 내놔!
- 싫어!
- Give it to me!
- You're crazy!
으! 지독한 계집애!
Damn you, Monica Geller hyphen Bing!
몰래 나가서 공중전화
쓸 생각하지마!
Don't even think of sneaking out
and using a pay phone..
내 감시망을
뚫을순 없을 테니깐!
because I am everywhere, baby!
안녕! 조이가 왔어!
친구도 데려왔지!
Hey, look who's here. It's Joey.
And he brought home a friend.
엠마가 있잖아! 낮에는
여자 안데려오기로 약속했잖아!
Emma's right here. You promised not to
bring girls home in the middle of the day!
여자 아냐!
No, no, no, it's not a girl. It's..
새 헉시인형이야!
a brand-new Huggsy!
어머! 근사하다!
엠마한테 헉시가 둘 생겼네!
Oh! Oh, that's so great!
Now Emma has two Huggsies!
아냐, 아냐!
엠마는 새 헉시 하나만
No, no. Oh, no.
No, Emma has one Huggsy.
갖는거야
The new Huggsy.
다른 헉시는
내가 다시 가져갈래
The other Huggsy, I don't know,
I guess I'll just take him back.
그거 알아? 난 어렸을 때 코튼이라는
분홍색 망아지 인형이 있었어
You know what? When I was a little girl,
I had a little pink pony named Cotton.
정말 좋아했지, 어디든 갖고 다니고
맨날 꼬리도 땋아주고..
Oh, I loved her so much. I took her
everywhere. I would braid her tail..
빨리 바꿔주기나 해!
Make the transfer!
헉시 단추가 하나 떨어졌던데
못찾겠어, 어쩌지?
Should I be concerned that a button fell
off the old Huggsy and I can't find it?
괜찮아
몇년전에 내가 삼켰어
No, don't worry about it.
I swallowed that years ago. Hey!
왜? 엠마가 새 헉시는
마음에 안드나봐
Oh, what? I don't think
she likes the new Huggsy.
똑같은걸?
- But he's the same.
- I think she wants the old one back.
옛날 헉시 다시 달라는것 같은데?
- 그거나 이거나 똑같아!
- 조이, 빨리줘
- Yeah, but he's the same.
- Joey, come on.
똑같단 말야!
But he's the same!
하나도 안똑같아!
You're not the same.
내가 아파트 현관문 열어줬는데
You know, it's a lot
less surprising to do that..
그런다고 놀라겠니?
after I've buzzed you
into the building.
피비, 문앞에
왜 남자신발이 있지?
So, Phoebe, why are there
men's shoes by the door?
그건 내거야
Those are my shoes.
너 이번일 넘기고 나면
당장 쇼핑부터 가자
Well, when you get over this breakup,
we need to go shopping.
신경 써줘서 고마운데
Look, Monica, I really appreciate
you checking in on me.
- 나 벌써 많이 나아졌어
- 정말?
- But I'm actually feeling a lot better.
- You are?
그래, 지금은 좀 혼자있고 싶어
Yeah, I just kind of want
to be alone right now.
- 누구야?
- 중국음식 시켰어
- Who's that?
- I ordered Chinese food.
기막힌 우연이네!
What are the chances?!
10억 중국인 중에서 하필
마이크가 배달을 오다니!
One billion Chinese people,
and they send Mike!
- 여긴 웬일이죠?
- 피비가 전화했어요
- What are you doing here?
- Phoebe called me.
- 피비!
- 미안해! 참을수 없었어!
- Phoebe!
- I'm sorry. I broke down.
보고싶은데 어떡해!
I wanted to see him.
내가 지키는데 그러면 안되지
Well, not on my watch.
도대체 어떻게
전화를 걸었지?
Damn it, Phoebe,
how did you even call him?
전화기 본체에
스피커폰이 달렸잖아
There's a speakerphone
on the base unit.
맞다! 바보 같은 모니카!
머리좀 써라!
Base unit. Think, Monica, think!
- 들어가도 돼요?
- 안돼요
- Can I come in?
- No! No.
피비, 이런일이 일어나는걸
막기 위해서 감시를 부탁했잖아
Phoebe, isn't seeing Mike exactly what
you wanted me to stop you from doing?
- 나도 피비가 보고싶고 피비도 날..
- 댁하곤 상관없는 일이에요!
- Look, if I want to see Phoebe, and she..
- This doesn't concern you!
미안해요, 내 이름이 나와서
헷갈렸나봐요
Sorry. I guess I was thrown off
by the mention of my name.
두사람 이러면 안돼요
Look, guys, you can't do this.
이럴수록 둘다
더 힘들어진다구요
It's gonna make getting
over each other harder.
아무일 안생기면 되잖아
그냥 친구처럼 놀께
Not if nothing happens.
Why can't we just hang out as friends?
그래, 좋아, 친구처럼 놀거라면
나도 같이 놀자
Sure. If you're just gonna hang out
as friends, then maybe I'll join you.
나도 네 친구고
마이크도 친구잖아
You know, I'm your friend
and Mike's friend.
앉아요
Sit down.
친구 자리도 좀 만들어줘
Make room for your friend.
- 어떻게 지냈어요?
- 잘 지냈어요
- So how have you been?
- I've been pretty good.
- 정말 예뻐요
- 고마워요, 마이크도 좋아 보여요
- You look really beautiful.
- Thanks. You look good too.
안돼, 안돼! 여긴 위험지역이야!
접근하지 말아요
No, no, no. This is dangerous territory.
Keep it clean.
피아노 치는건 잘되구요?
So how's the piano playing going?
요즘은 사랑노래를
많이 연주해요
Actually, I've been playing a lot
of love songs lately.
- 보고싶었어요
- 나도 보고싶었어요
- I've missed you.
- I've missed you too.
오다 보니까 어떤 사람이
술 취해서 토했는데
You know, on the way over here,
I saw this drunk guy throw up.
그걸 비둘기가 먹는거 있지!
And then a pigeon ate it.
로스?
Hey. Ross.
사과하러 왔어
Look, I just wanted to apologize.
내 얼굴 넣은 저 게이 사진
진짜 네가 만든거야?
Don't tell me you actually made
those gay pictures of me.
그래, 이것봐
Check this out.
내가 운동을 열심히 하면
저렇게 되는구나
So that's what I'd look like
if I worked out.
그리고 경찰관의
서비스를 받는단 말이지
And was being serviced
by a policeman.
저 사진 진짜로 동창회 사이트에
올릴건 아니지?
You're not gonna actually
send these out, are you?
맞아, 그럴 필요가 없어졌어
네 농담이 전혀 안먹혀들었거든
Actually, I don't need to, because your
little "Ross is dead" joke didn't work.
답글 올린 사람도 아무도 없고
Okay? There were no responses.
부모님한테 전화한 사람도 없어
그러니까 너 혼자 쇼 한거야!
Nobody posted anything, nobody called
my parents, so the joke is on you.
전화도, 메일도 없었어!
신경쓰는 사람 아무도 없다구!
Nobody called, nobody wrote anything,
nobody cares that I'm dead.
맙소사!
Oh, my God.
내가 죽어도
신경쓰는 사람이 아무도 없어?!
- Nobody cares that I'm dead?
- Oh, come on, you know that's not true.
그렇지 않다는거 잘 알잖아
무슨 소리야!
넌 게이선언 하고
What are you talking about?
You get 60 responses..
무려 60명한테서
연락 받았잖아!
just for coming out of the closet.
난 죽었는데도
연락 한통 못받았다구!
I didn't get one response,
and I'm dead!
원래 게이들이 죽은 사람들보다
입이 싸거든
Well, the gay community is a lot more
vocal than the dead community.
지질학과 연구실 동료조차도
연락이 없어! 내가 키우다시피 했는데!
I can't believe this. Not even my geology
lab partner. And I carried that guy!
생각해봐
Look, let's think about this, okay?
너 같으면 슬픔에 잠긴
네 가족들한테 냉큼 전화하겠니?
You think people are gonna disturb
your family at this tragic time?
너 같으면 웹사이트에
애도의 글을 올리겠어?
That people are gonna post condolences
on a website?
사람들이 네 죽음에
관심이 없어서가 아냐
This isn't about people not caring.
애도를 표시할 방법이
마땅히 없기 때문이라구
This is about people not having
a decent outlet for their grief.
- 맞아! 마땅한 방법이 없지
- 장례식이나
- You're right. There isn't a decent outlet.
- Right.
추모 행사 같은게 있다면
구름 떼같이 몰려 올거야
I'm sure if you had a funeral or memorial
service, tons of people would come.
맞아!
Exactly!
로스, 뭐하는 거야?
Ross, what are you doing?
네가 네 추모행사를
연다는 거야?
You're having a memorial service
for yourself?
아니, 그건 코미디지
네가 대신 열어줘
No, that would be stupid.
You're having it for me.
- '전송' 누르지마! 누르면 안돼!
- 너무 늦었어! 벌써 보냈는걸
- Ross, don't press send. Don't press..
- No, too late. Too late. It's sent.
미안, 너랑 경찰관 사진도
전송됐다!
Sorry, so is that picture
of you and the policeman.
괜찮아, 피부색도 멋지게 탔고
거기다 유연하잖아
That's all right. I'm tan, limber..
그리고 교통위반벌금도
안내도 되겠네
And it looks like I talked my way
out of that ticket.
수술은 성공이었어
네 차례야
The surgery was not a success.
And then you say:
"이일을 어떻게 하죠, 드레이크?"
"What are we gonna do, Drake?"
들어와
Come in.
엠마 낮잠 재워야 하는데
헉시 못봤니?
I'm trying to put Emma down for a nap.
Have you seen Huggsy?
오리지널? 아니면 짜가?
Original or crappy?
- 오리지널
- 아니, 난 못봤어
- Original.
- No. Sorry. Haven't seen him.
이불 밑에 그 불룩한건 뭐야?
Then what's that big lump
under your covers?
- 모니카야!
- 모니카 아니잖아!
- It's Monica, okay?
- That's not Monica!
그래, 좋아!
오리지널 헉시다!
All right, fine! It's original Huggsy!
얜 내꺼고 나한테도 필요하다구!
I know Emma wants him,
but he's mine and I need him.
이걸 달라는건 억지라구!
She's being unreasonable.
엠마가 그 한심한 펭귄을 그렇게
좋아하는덴 다 이유가 있어!
Joey, there is a reason that Emma
loves that stupid penguin so much!
헉시 귀 막지마!
Oh, don't cover its ears!
조이 삼촌을 생각나게 하기
때문에 좋아하는 거란 말야!
It's because it reminds her
of her Uncle Joey.
- 그런거야?
- 그래
- It does?
- Yeah.
그리고 인형에서 네 냄새가 나서
좋아하는것 같아
And I think she really likes him
because he smells like you.
네 냄새를 좋아한다구
And she.. She loves that.
이해는 안되지만
Go figure.
조이 삼촌을 너무나 사랑하니까
헉시를 보고 좋아하는 거라구
And she's comforted by him because
she loves her Uncle Joey so much.
- 정말? 엠마가 나 사랑해?
- 그럼
- Really? She loves me?
- Oh, yeah.
하지만 할수없지, 네가 헉시를
갖고 싶다는데 어쩌겠어
But you know what?
If you need Huggsy, don't worry.
엠마도 이해할거야
난 이해 못하겠지만
Emma will totally understand.
I won't, but whatever.
잠깐, 잠깐만! 레이첼!
Okay, wait a minute, Rach.
I mean, if..
엠마에게 우리 헉시가
그렇게 소중하다면
If Huggsy means that much
to Emma, then..
엠마한테 줄께
Well, she can have him.
고마워! 조이 삼촌이
양보해줄 줄 알았어
Oh, sweet, I knew Uncle Joey
would step up.
- 엠마, 이것봐라?
- 안돼! 취소야! 헉시는 못줘!
- Look, Emma. Look who's back.
- No, forget it! Forget it! I can't do it!
기가 막혀! 어린애한테서
인형을 빼앗겠다는 거야?
Are you..? You're gonna take
Huggsy away from a little child?
헉시 처음에 데려올 때도
그랬는데, 뭐!
How do you think I got him
in the first place?
토한걸 다 먹어치우더라고
And then it just gobbled up that puke.
I mean..
정말 끔직한 비둘기였어
That was one gross pigeon.
조이한테 날 감시해달라고 할걸
Oh, man. Why didn't I ask Joey
to keep us apart?
고깃덩어리를 밖으로 던지고
둘이서 재미보면 될텐데
You throw a meatball in the hallway,
we'd be doing it like rabbits right now.
두사람 잘 들어요
나 화장실 다녀 올테니까
All right, you two.
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
나 볼일 보는동안
아무짓도 하면 안돼
I don't want anything going
on while I'm gone.
두사람에게 허용되는
대화 주제는 다음과 같아
Here's a few things you can discuss:
점액, 곰팡이, 그리고 오빠와
내가 한 침대에 누워있는 상상
Mucus, fungus, and the idea
of me and Ross doing it.
정말 보고싶었어요
I've missed you so much.
다시 돌아가자고 하진 않을게요
우린 원하는게 다르니까..
I won't ask you to get back together.
I know we want different things, but..
다만 피비와 하룻밤만
더 함께 있고 싶어요
- Just to be with you one more night.
- I want that too.
나도 그러고 싶지만
- 더 힘들어지지 않을까요?
- 지금보다 더 힘들겠어요?
- But is that gonna make it too hard?
- It can't be any harder than this.
지난번 피비와의 만남이
마지막이 될줄 알았더라면
I mean, if I had known the last time
I saw you would be the last time, I..
피비의 얼굴, 몸짓 하나까지
기억해 뒀을 거예요
I would have stopped to memorize
your face, the way you moved.
당신에 대한 모든것을..
Everything about you.
지난번 키스가
마지막이 될줄 알았더라면
If I had known the last time I kissed
you would be the last time..
결코 멈추지 않았을 거예요
I never would have stopped.
빨리 키스해, 이 바보야!
Kiss him, you fool!
- 뭐?
- 방금 그말 못들었니?
- What?
- Didn't you hear that speech?
네가 키스 안하면
내가 해버릴 거야!
If you don't kiss him, then I will.
너무나 보고싶었어요!
I missed you so much.
- 여기 왔을줄 알았어!
- 아, 젠장!
- I knew you'd be here!
- Crap.
- 누구예요?
- 내 친구 매니예요
- Who is this?
- My friend Manny.
날 감시해달라고 부탁했죠
I asked him to keep me away from you.
- 난 피비를 감시하고 있어요
- 감시 참 잘하고 있군요
- Hey, that's what I'm doing for Phoebe.
- Well, you're not doing a very good job.
- 뭐라구요?
- 방금 그 키스는 뭐죠?
- Excuse me?
- What's with the kissing?
난 적어도 내 친구가
어디 있는지는 알고 있다구요!
Hey, at least I knew
where my guy was.
그래요? 둘이 키스하는거
구경만 해줘서 고맙군요!
Yeah, thank God you were here
to oversee all the kissing.
댁은 마이크의 말을
못들어서 그래요!
- You didn't hear the speech.
- I've heard the speech.
다 들었어요!
"지난번 만남이
마지막일줄 알았더라면.."
If he knew it was gonna
be the last time..
아주 감동적이었다구요!
참 매정한 사람이군요!
Hey, it was very moving.
You're just heartless!
- 댁은 의지가 약해요!
- 댁은 괴짜예요!
- You're weak!
- You're weird!
- 지퍼 열렸어요!
- 어머!
Your pants are undone.
두사람 어디 갔죠?
Where'd they go?
- 이런!
- 우리가 망쳤어요!
- Damn it.
- Well, we blew it.
내탓입니다
I blame myself.
맞아요! 그쪽 탓이에요!
And I blame you too.
한시간이 지났는데 어쩜
한명도 안나타나지?
It's been an hour, and not one
of my classmates has shown up?
나 진짜로 죽으면 몇사람은
꿈자리 엄청 사나울 거야!
I tell you, when I actually die, some
people are gonna get seriously haunted.
왔다! 조문객이 왔어!
There you go. Someone came.
알았어! 난 숨어 있을게!
Okay. Okay. I'm gonna go hide.
너무 신난다!
첫번째 조문객이야!
This is so exciting. My first mourner!
와주셔서 감사합니다
Hi. Glad you could come.
- 들어오세요
- 챈들러 빙 맞지?
- Please come in.
- Hi. You're Chandler Bing, right?
- 탐 고든이야, 같은 과였잖아
- 아, 그래, 코트 이리줘
- I'm Tom Gordon. I was in your class.
- Oh, yes. Yes, let me take your coat.
고마워
로스일은 정말 안됐어
Thanks. I'm so sorry
about Ross, it's..
그래도 좋아하는 일 하다가
가서 다행이야
No, at least he died doing
what he loved.
비행선 구경하는 일
Watching blimps.
- 누구야?
- 탐 고든이란 친구 알아?
- Who is it?
- You know some guy, Tom Gordon?
기억 안나는데?
I don't remember him.
하긴 내가 워낙 여러 사람한테
깊은 인상을 줬으니까
But then again,
I touched so many lives.
오빠랑 잘 아세요?
So did you know Ross well?
실은 잘 몰라요
챈들러 소식 듣고 온겁니다
Actually, I barely knew him.
I came because I heard Chandler's news.
그친구 요즘
만나는 사람 있나요?
Do you know if he's seeing anyone?
- 있어요, 바로 저예요
- 뭐라구요? 그렇다면.. 아!
- Yes, he is. Me.
- What? You mean..?
어떻게 수염을 그렇게
말끔히 깎았죠?
Can I ask you a personal question?
How do you shave your beard so close?
됐어, 탐!
그만큼 애도했으면 됐다구!
Okay, Tommy!
That's enough mourning for you.
여기있어! 잘가!
Here we go
Bye-bye. All right.
- 챈들러? 전화해!
- 알았어!
- Hey, listen. Call me.
- Okay.
내가 죽었는데
아무도 관심이 없어?
- I'm dead and no one cares?
- I look like a man?
내가 남자 같아 보여?!
한심한 질문은
한번에 하나씩만 해!
Please, one ridiculous problem
at a time.
한심한게 아냐!
봐! 아무도 없잖아!
This isn't ridiculous.
Look around, no one's here.
겨우 어제 글 올렸잖아!
아직 못본 사람이 많을 거라구!
You gave them one day's notice. Not
everyone checks the website every day.
자긴 서있는 폼 때문에
오해받은 걸거야!
And Monica, it's probably
the way you stand!
네말이 맞아, 그래도 내소식
본 사람이 있을거 아냐!
I guess you're right.
Still, somebody must have seen it.
4년이나 학교 다녔는데 날
기억해주는 사람이 그렇게 없어?
I went to that school for four years
and I didn't have an impact on anyone?
그렇지 않아
내가 있잖아
Well, that's not true.
You had an impact on me.
15년이 지난 지금도 우린 친구야
I mean, it's 15 years later
and we're still best friends.
그건 의미가 없어?
Doesn't that count for something?
챈들러의 파티손님이
또 왔나보군
Oh, great, more party boys
for Chandler.
분명히 너 때문에 온 사람일 거야
빨리 숨어!
I'm sure it's somebody for you.
Now go hide.
안녕하세요? 로스의
추모회가 있다고 해서 왔어요
Hi. I'm here for Ross Geller's
memorial service.
- 코리? 코리 웨스턴?
- 그런데요?
- Kori? Kori Weston?
- Yeah.
- 정말 근사한데!
- 누구시죠?
- You look amazing.
- And you are?
챈들러 빙
나 절대 게이 아냐
Chandler. Chandler Bing.
And I'm not gay. I'm not gay at all.
그리고 유부남이죠
You are married, though.
저녀석 말 듣지마
지금 기분이 엉망이거든
Don't listen to him.
He's in a really bad mood.
로스가 갔다니 믿어지지 않아
정말 슬픈 일이야
I can't believe that Ross is gone.
It is just so sad.
로스와 친한줄 몰랐어
I didn't know Ross and you
were so close.
친하지 않았지만 같은 과였어
정말 멋진 애였는데
Oh, we weren't. But we had one class
together. He was such a great guy.
과학에 대해 얘기할땐
정말 열정적이었지
And he talked so passionately
about science.
- 늘 기억하고 있었어
- 로스가 기뻐할 거야
- I always remembered him.
- I'm sure that would mean a lot to him.
천국에 문이 있다면
And if heaven has a door..
지금쯤 문에 귀를
바짝 대고 듣고 있을걸
I'm sure he's pressing his ear
up against it and listening intently.
전화해서 만나자고 해볼까
망설이곤 했는데
I thought so many times about
calling him and asking him out.
이젠 영영 기회가 없겠지
I guess I really missed my chance.
아냐!
No, you didn't!
나 살아 있어!
I'm still alive!
그럼 누굴 묻은거야?
Who did we bury?
코리, 놀랐지?
Kori, I know this
is a big surprise for you.
사정이 있었어! 방금 네 얘기듣고
얼마나 기뻤는줄 알아?
It's a long story. But the things you
just said really made my day.
조문객으로 방이 꽉찬 것보다
The fact that you're here
means more to me..
네가 와준게 더 기뻐
than if this room were filled
with people.
완전히 미쳤어!
너 제정신이야?
You sick freak! Who does that?
내가 너같은 애한테 반했다니!
I can't believe I had a crush on you.
저말 들었어?
Did you hear that?
코리 웨스턴이 나한테
반했었대!
Kori Weston had a crush on me!
아뇨, 저 안죽었어요
No, Mom, I am not dead.
장난할 일 아닌거 저도 알죠
I know it's not something
to kid about.
챈들러랑 장난친다는게
도가 지나쳤어요, 이젠 다 끝났어요
It was just a practical joke between
Chandler and me, but it's over, okay?
제가 죽는다 해도 두분께
자식이 없는건 아니잖아요?
Actually, no. Even if I had died,
you would not be left childless.
모니카가 있잖아요?!
Monica?